<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3rd Party on NZCSIRR</title><link>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/categories/3rd-party/</link><description>Recent content in 3rd Party on NZCSIRR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/categories/3rd-party/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lantech cyber security incident</title><link>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/p/lantech-cyber-security-incident/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/p/lantech-cyber-security-incident/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impacted Agency:&lt;/strong>)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lantech - Auckland IT provider (now &lt;a class="link" href="https://cogent.co.nz/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://cogent.co.nz/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impact:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Lantech chief executive Ray Noonan told the Herald, “On May 29, Lantech experienced a cyber security incident impacting its vOffice platform with a limited number of customers impacted.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“As soon as Lantech became aware of this issue we engaged external specialist support, our investigations are in the early stages, and we have informed and are working with the relevant government agencies.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>“We have communicated directly with the customers impacted by this event and are in contact with the office of the Privacy Commissioner.”&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>References:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>NZ Herald: Fenz IT supplier hit by cyberattack, emergency services operational &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nzherald.co.nz/business/fenz-it-supplier-hit-by-cyberattack-emergency-services-not-affected/GCQM3YBKCBCZJCB5ADRLBAP2M4/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.nzherald.co.nz/business/fenz-it-supplier-hit-by-cyberattack-emergency-services-not-affected/GCQM3YBKCBCZJCB5ADRLBAP2M4/&lt;/a> or &lt;a class="link" href="https://archive.ph/SPLQn" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://archive.ph/SPLQn&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Following an anonymous tip-off to the Herald, Auckland-based IT services firm Lantech has confirmed it’s been hit by a cyberattack.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fire and Emergency New Zealand (Fenz) features as a customer case study on Lantech’s website.
Neither party would comment on the cyberattack, with Lantech refusing to comment on individual customers and Fenz referring questions to the IT services company.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>NZTA- Transport Agency privacy breach: 1500 motorists' information illegally accessed</title><link>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/p/nzta-transport-agency-privacy-breach-1500-motorists-information-illegally-accessed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/p/nzta-transport-agency-privacy-breach-1500-motorists-information-illegally-accessed/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impacted Agency:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>NZTA - New Zealand Transport Agency&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impact:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1,480 individuals had their personal information held on the Driver Licence Register (DLR) or Motor Vehicle Register (MVR) has been illegally accessed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The information accessed includes customers’ full name and address, or the status, conditions and endorsements on their driver licences.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>References:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>RNZ - Transport Agency privacy breach: 1500 motorists&amp;rsquo; information illegally accessed &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/national/517635/transport-agency-privacy-breach-1500-motorists-information-illegally-accessed" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/national/517635/transport-agency-privacy-breach-1500-motorists-information-illegally-accessed&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NZTA investigating privacy breach following illegal access of information held on driver licence and motor vehicle registers [https://www.nzta.govt.nz/media-releases/nzta-investigating-privacy-breach-following-illegal-access-of-information-held-on-driver-licence-and-motor-vehicle-registers/]&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A motor vehicle trader with authorised access to the DLR and the MVR had their account compromised. NZTA also notified the New Zealand Police and the Office of the Privacy Commissioner.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The illegally accessed information was gained through MotorWeb, a third-party on-line portal, after the identity of a motor vehicle trader and its staff was used to create a fraudulent account to access information held on the MVR and DLR.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Latitude cyber attack</title><link>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/p/latitude-cyber-attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/p/latitude-cyber-attack/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impacted Agency:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Latitude (although this is an Australian company it had an impact on many New Zealanders)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Latitude Financial Services Limited NZ provides a wide range of financial and (limited) insurance services to customers across New Zealand via Gem Finance and Gem Visa and several subsidiary groups.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Latitude Financial Services Limited NZ is a subsidiary of Latitude Holdings based in Australia.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Latitude Financial have estimated that 14 million NZ and Australian customer records have been exposed because of the 12 March attack of which around 1.08 million are NZ customer records.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The 1.08 million NZ customer records includes around 1.037 million driver license records, around 40,000 passport records and sensitive income and expense information. The income and expenditure information was submitted as part of a personal loan application process.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impact:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Customers and applicants in Australia and New Zealand who had one or more of the following compromised:&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Approximately 7.9 million driver licence numbers and some but not necessarily all of: name, address, telephone and date of birth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Approximately 103,000 copies of driver licences or passports&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Approximately 53,000 passport numbers&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Less than 100 monthly account statements&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Income and expense information used to assess approximately 900,000 loan applications, including approximately 308,000 bank account numbers (but not passwords) for the disbursement of funds and approximately 143,000 credit card or credit card account numbers (but not card expiry or 3-digit CVC) for debt consolidation, the overwhelming majority of which are expired or closed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Where needed Latitude reimbursed customers for the replacement cost of their stolen ID document.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>References:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Latitude &amp;ldquo;Statement of Notification&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.latitudefinancial.com.au/cyber-statement-of-notification" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.latitudefinancial.com.au/cyber-statement-of-notification&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Latitude Cyber Response &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.latitudefinancial.com.au/latitude-cyber-incident/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.latitudefinancial.com.au/latitude-cyber-incident/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NZ Privacy Commissioner: &amp;ldquo;New Zealand-Australia investigation into Latitude breach begins&amp;rdquo; &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.privacy.org.nz/publications/statements-media-releases/new-zealand-australia-investigation-into-latitude-breach-begins/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.privacy.org.nz/publications/statements-media-releases/new-zealand-australia-investigation-into-latitude-breach-begins/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>GemFinance: &amp;ldquo;Latitude Cyber Incident Update&amp;rdquo; (original de-published, link to archive.org) &lt;a class="link" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20240508040501/https://gemfinance.zendesk.com/hc/en-nz/articles/13777730237713-Latitude-Cyber-Incident-Update" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://web.archive.org/web/20240508040501/https://gemfinance.zendesk.com/hc/en-nz/articles/13777730237713-Latitude-Cyber-Incident-Update&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NZTA on replacement of NZ driver license: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.nzta.govt.nz/driver-licences/latitude-financial-services-data-incident/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.nzta.govt.nz/driver-licences/latitude-financial-services-data-incident/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RNZ Three months after Latitude cyberattack, some victims still not notified &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/national/492222/three-months-after-latitude-cyberattack-some-victims-still-not-notified" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/national/492222/three-months-after-latitude-cyberattack-some-victims-still-not-notified&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>On 16 March 2023, Latitude1 announced that it had experienced a malicious cyber-attack over the prior few days that resulted in a data theft.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Our investigation identified that the cybercriminals used a compromised credential, obtained via a third-party, to access Latitude&amp;rsquo;s network and steal personal information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We immediately alerted relevant authorities and law enforcement agencies, including the Australian Cyber Security Centre (ACSC) and the Australian Federal Police (AFP), and engaged external cyber security specialists to work alongside our own teams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This crime remains under investigation by the AFP. We also notified the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC) and the New Zealand Office of the Privacy Commissioner (OPC) about the incident on 16 March 2023, and we continue to work with them.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>RBNZ - Accellion File Transfer Application (FTA) data breach</title><link>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/p/rbnz-accellion-file-transfer-application-fta-data-breach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cramsthaler.github.io/NZCSIRR/p/rbnz-accellion-file-transfer-application-fta-data-breach/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impacted Agency:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>RBNZ - Reserve Bank of New Zealand&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Impact:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A file-sharing application, known as Accellion, had been compromised, potentially exposing personal and commercially sensitive information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We estimate the final cost of the breach response, including internal resources, will be around $3.5 million. This excludes any process improvement initiatives we are likely to take as a result of the lessons learnt. All costs associated with the breach were covered under our baseline budgets. The main details of the costs include:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>17,500 hours of internal resources redirected to help with the response&lt;/li>
&lt;li>$1,800,000 spent on specialist external resources, these being individuals to supplement our staff on the stream activity or organisations delivering a defined piece of work.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>References:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Reserve Bank responding to illegal breach of data system &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.rbnz.govt.nz/hub/news/2021/01/reserve-bank-responding-to-illegal-breach-of-data-system" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.rbnz.govt.nz/hub/news/2021/01/reserve-bank-responding-to-illegal-breach-of-data-system&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RBNZ - Our response to the data breach &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.rbnz.govt.nz/about-us/responsibility-and-accountability/our-response-to-the-data-breach" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.rbnz.govt.nz/about-us/responsibility-and-accountability/our-response-to-the-data-breach&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>KPMG report &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.rbnz.govt.nz/-/media/project/sites/rbnz/files/data-breach/kpmg-incident-assessment.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.rbnz.govt.nz/-/media/project/sites/rbnz/files/data-breach/kpmg-incident-assessment.pdf&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Privacy Commissioner: Compliance Notice issued to Reserve Bank of New Zealand following cyber attack &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.privacy.org.nz/publications/statements-media-releases/compliance-notice-issued-to-reserve-bank-of-new-zealand-following-cyber-attack/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.privacy.org.nz/publications/statements-media-releases/compliance-notice-issued-to-reserve-bank-of-new-zealand-following-cyber-attack/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>RBNZ governor &amp;lsquo;apologises unreservedly&amp;rsquo; for data breach &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/434593/rbnz-governor-apologises-unreservedly-for-data-breach" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/434593/rbnz-governor-apologises-unreservedly-for-data-breach&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reserve Bank of New Zealand says it wasn&amp;rsquo;t directly targeted in cyber attack &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/434359/reserve-bank-of-new-zealand-says-it-wasn-t-directly-targeted-in-cyber-attack" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/business/434359/reserve-bank-of-new-zealand-says-it-wasn-t-directly-targeted-in-cyber-attack&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accellion&amp;rsquo;s failure to warn RBNZ of exploited bug led to hack &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.itnews.com.au/news/accellions-failure-to-warn-rbnz-of-exploited-bug-led-to-hack-565323" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>https://www.itnews.com.au/news/accellions-failure-to-warn-rbnz-of-exploited-bug-led-to-hack-565323&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Summary:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The hack took place on Christmas Day 2020, and the RBNZ went public about the data breach on January 11, noting it included commercially and personally sensitive information.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;We have been advised by the third party provider that this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a specific attack on the Reserve Bank, and other users of the file sharing application were also compromised,&amp;rdquo; Orr said.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A certification and accreditation process to understand and ensure that any key risks were identified and managed had not been done on the FTA by RBNZ.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Unauthorised access was obtained to a third-party developed file transfer system, Accellion File Transfer Application (FTA) (“the System”) used by the Bank in late 2020. This access was obtained by exploiting a previously unknown vulnerability in the FTA application.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>